<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hi, I'm Joseph! 👋]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 18:08:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Books]]></title><description><![CDATA[Coming Soon]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/books/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/books/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Desktop Apps]]></title><description><![CDATA[Coming Soon]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/desktop-apps/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/desktop-apps/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></title><description><![CDATA[Coming Soon]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/mobile-apps/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/mobile-apps/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[January]]></title><description><![CDATA[“Enjoy the little things, for one day you may look back and realize they were the big things.” Robert Brault  January 1 As it was the start…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/january/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/january/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Enjoy the little things, for one day you may look back and realize they were the big things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Brault&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./winter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As it was the start of 2022, I got to have an amazing discussion with my family. We got to essentially reflect on how 2021 has been for each of us and it opened room for conservations we usually don’t get to have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made my new years resolution to start off the year strong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated my monthly habit tracker to make sure it corresponds with my New Years Goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today, along with my family, I went to Ottawa to pick up my things from when I lived there during my last co-op term. My cousin and her husband who was there, treated us to Popeyes so the food was delicious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished listening to the audio book, “Think Like a Monk” by Jay Shetty. It was such an amazing book and it gave me additional clarity on how I want to live my life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once we were home, I set up my computer and it feels good to have it again compared to my laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started practicing piano again! I’ve been avoiding it for quite some time now due to other responsibilities but I’m happy I managed to make time for it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I’m still on break, I got to enjoy my day by playing League of Legends with my brothers and cousins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started a new book called “Outliers: The Story of Success” by Malcolm Gladwell, and so far it’s pretty exciting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I woke up at 6am today! I finally fixed my sleep schedule and starting the day in the morning substantially increased my productivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My mom had a high workload for her immigration business and I was able to help lessen her load by doing data entry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got in my exercise for the day which was cardio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realized that I should always follow a schedule whenever I want to get things done. This is much better than the alternative of doing things in the moment as there’s a higher chance that I’ll get distracted from my what I want to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do 10 min of typing practice a day and I can tell that my speed is slowly increasing. I’m able to reach speeds of over 100 WPM now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had lots of fun playing osu, a computer rhythm game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My motivation to go to the gym was extremely low but that didn’t stop me from exercising today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished replying to LetterLoop, which is a series of engaging that I answer and talk about with my friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent a good chunk of my day wasting my time, but I managed to spend the remainder of my day doing productive and meaningful activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 7&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Held myself more accountable today by sharing my Google Calendar to others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took a new approach to the side project that I’m working on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed 80% of my habits today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 8&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued reading “Outliers” by Malcolm Gladwell. I really like how he talks about how people don’t become successful purely due to hard work but also due to the opportunities that are given to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As it was the weekend, I had fun playing League of Legends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can tell that my piano skills are slowly improving the more I practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 9&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After our family attended church, we got to have a good discussion together as a family. I really enjoy these times as it’s an opportunity where everyone in our family gets to speak and is open with one another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My friend gave me a custom mouse pad as a belated birthday gift! It was such an amazing gift as it was also One Piece themed and matched my computer set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I updated my Notion template. I’m extremely happy with how it turned out and this makes me more excited to use it on a daily basis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 10&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got to save a little bit of money as I changed one of monthly subscriptions to the yearly option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I’m coming back from the winter break, I’m slowly getting used to studying again. Eventually I’ll be able to go back to my natural rhythm of things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brainstormed lots of amazing ideas of how I want to create my website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 11&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I almost finished one of my assignments! This is due in 2 weeks and yet I already 70% of the content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started using the Alarmy App to help me wake up early in the morning and start being productive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished what I needed to do so I relaxed the evening by playing League of Legends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 12&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found a new site called Optimize Me which gives thoughtful summaries for self help books and other topics to help you succeed in life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My motivation was still low today but I managed to practice piano and continue exercising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned about Gatsby and how the bootstrapping process works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 13&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started listening to audio books again. This saves me so much time as I can still do other tasks while listening to the book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The book I started listening to was “Man’s Search for Meaning” by Viktor Frankl. So far it’s such an amazing book and I love learning about his perspectives on life, success, and happiness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished my economics quiz and I feel pretty good with how it went.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 14&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I realized that listening to an audio book gives me an incentive to exercise more as there aren’t that many other tasks that I can do while listening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated my Cold Turkey Blocker settings to reduce my distractions and help me enter a state of deep focus throughout the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a contract my friends to finish my side project before a certain deadline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 15&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I managed to enter a state of deep focus for 6 hours today. I blocked every single app and web application that distracted me and all that was left for me was just work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also had lots of fun playing osu today as I can tell that I’m getting better at the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had a call with a long-time friend whom I haven’t spoken to for a couple of months. We got to catch up on life, have meaningful conversations, and overall just a good time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 16&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My personal website is now up and running! There is still some more elements that need to be added but I’m super satisfied with the progress I’ve made.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of my cousins came over and it was a lot of fun just hanging out with them. My Dad also ordered pizza for all of us so we had a nice meal together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My average phone screen time from last week was 29 minutes. This was probably one of the lowest screen times I’ve ever had.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 17&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woke up late today but I was still able to finish my tasks for the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared my website to my family and friends and they really liked it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished going through the job application process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 18&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went through my geography lectures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed my economics practice problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did the laundry and cleaned my room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 19&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed my workout for the day and I also slightly increased the weight size for benchpress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reached a typing speed of 110 WPM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ended the night by playing games with my cousins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 20&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solved all the problems from my economics homework set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also finished completing my quiz today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bought a brand new webcam with a much higher quality!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 21&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helped out my younger brother and cousin film a music video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was a little cold today so I made hot chocolate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today was family movie night day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 22&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blocked League of Legends for a week so I can focus more on school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took a break from my habit tracker to focus on other things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a contract with my friends to help me wake up earlier again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 23&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed my geography lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slowly catching up in my CS lectures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vacuumed the house today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 24&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woke up at 6am today!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started taking notes of book summaries from “Optimize Me.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had chicken wings for dinner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 25&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished my economics assignment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went through self help book summaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After 8pm, I relaxed for the rest of the night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 26&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished work simulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewed objects and other Python data structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I no longer need to take naps to wake up at 6am.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 27&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purchased Leetcode premium!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed my economics quiz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercised and practiced the piano today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 28&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished my geography quiz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practiced more Leetcode questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued helping my brother and cousin film their music video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 29&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started a new side project!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had lots of fun hanging out with my cousins today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The dinner today was from Pizza Hut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 30&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did some grocery shopping today with my parents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved in to my place at Waterloo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First day I met my roommates, and they’re all super nice people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;January 31&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had enough cooked food in the fridge so I didn’t have to cook today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slowly getting used to living on my own again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished my geography lab for the week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[February]]></title><description><![CDATA[“Be grateful for what you already have while you pursue your goals.
If you aren’t grateful for what you already have, what makes you think…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/february/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/february/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Be grateful for what you already have while you pursue your goals.
If you aren’t grateful for what you already have, what makes you think you would be happy with more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roy T. Bennett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;February 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woke up at 5 am today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went through all my CS exercises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My roommate hosted a small dinner party which was a lot of fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;February 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did a lot better than I expected than in my CS assignment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submitted my geography lab in less than 4 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had fun spending the night playing league with my family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;February 12&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After taking a long break, started my gratitude journal again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went through my economics homework set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went to bed before 10pm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Deep Focus]]></title><description><![CDATA[“what we choose to focus on and what we choose to ignore—plays in defining the quality of our life.” Cal Newport Before the pandemic, I used…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/deep-focus/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/deep-focus/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“what we choose to focus on and what we choose to ignore—plays in defining the quality of our life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cal Newport&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the pandemic, I used to be the student who lived in the library. That is how I entered a study environment and started my work. However, once the pandemic hit, the libraries closed and school became online. At first, it was nearly impossible for me to study for even 10 minutes without experiencing a distraction. Now, 2 to 3 years later, I learned how to overcome my distractions and I can focus for up to 3 to 4 hours without taking a single break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 Minute Rule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often the hardest part of studying is getting started. For me personally, if the work I have to do is overwhelming then it can cause fear and anxiety which leads to procrastination. The 5 minute rules helps target this aspect of procrastination and it essentially shows you that the work is not scary as you think it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way it works is that you make a goal to focus for only 5 minutes and after those 5 minutes are up, you are allowed to stop. This doesn’t sound like much, but this allows you to gain momentum and by the time your 5 minutes are up, the work I’m doing no longer feels scary and I don’t want to stop since I just started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may not know if I can actually complete the work I have for the day, but I do know that I can work for 5 minutes and then keep going from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distraction Journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While studying, sometimes random thoughts appear in my mind to prevent from me studying. For example, one time I was studying and I looked at my trashcan and saw that it was full. It gave me a sudden urge to stop what I’m doing and take out the trash. I don’t want to ignore it because I might forget later on and it’s a super quick task so what’s the harm? I took out the trash, went back to my room, and then I no longer felt like doing work. I lost my studying momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I use a distraction journal for situations like these. If I have a sudden urge to do something, I just write it down in my journal and then go back to work. It sounds super simple but writing those things down helps you avoid thinking them which allows you to focus on the task at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Blocker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For sites such as YouTube and Instagram, they are deliberately designed for maximum distraction. So it’s no surprise whenever I go on YouTube and find myself spending hours of my day watching random YouTube videos. Even if I try to stay away using sheer willpower, I often find myself coming back to those sites again and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using web blockers, it doesn’t matter how much willpower I have. It’s impossible for me to be distracted by sites that I do not have access to. If something is blocked, the urge for me to access those sites also disappears. Now I can preserve my willpower for something more meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Power of Accountability]]></title><description><![CDATA[“I believe that accountability is the basis of all meaningful human achievement.” Sam Silverstein Whenever I find myself in a slump and I…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/power-of-accountability/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/power-of-accountability/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I believe that accountability is the basis of all meaningful human achievement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam Silverstein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I find myself in a slump and I don’t want to do anything, I often ask my friends and family for help to give me the push that I need. I found that whenever I ask for someone to keep my accountable, my productivity skyrockets and I’m able to achieve things that I never thought were possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Practical Ways to Keep Yourself Accountable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contracts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With someone close to you, ask them for a quick favour. Make a contract that publicly states if you don’t complete X task, then you’ll receive Y consequence. For example, I once told my friends that if I don’t finish my assignment before a certain time period, then I’ll give them a monetary reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing this, my motivation has increased substantially which allows me to get my work done. Even if you end up violating your contract, the work you get done is often higher than it would have been if you didn’t make a contract in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accountability Partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, by having someone who can always keep you accountable, that helps motivate you to keep the work you need. On a daily or weekly basis, an accountability partner can be someone who talks to you about what your goals are and then check up on you after a certain period of time to see how you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I know that someone will check up on me, it essentially forces me to do my work.  Unless I had a valid excuse, it is often pretty painful to say that I didn’t finish what I wanted and it’s even worse if it because of laziness. I don’t want to tell them I did nothing because I was lazy as that would be letting them down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared Habit Trackers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a habit tracker, I find them most accountable when you show your progress towards others. I don’t want people to see a long streak of my incomplete habits, so the only option I have that is left is to put in the work and stay consistent with my habits. This also gives me the incentive I need to complete my habits because I want to be able to show and be proud of my accomplishments that I’m able to stay consistent with the habits that I want in my life.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Time Management Tips]]></title><description><![CDATA[Shared Google Calendar This is my favourite time management tool, and I would say it was pretty life changing. My friends and I came up with…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/time-management/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/time-management/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared Google Calendar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my favourite time management tool, and I would say it was pretty life changing. My friends and I came up with this idea where we created a google calendar where we put in tasks that we really want to get done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each task in our calendar, we always check up with each other to see how we are doing and that the task actually gets completed. By knowing that my friends are going to message me, it makes me feel pretty motivated and since it’s my friends I don’t want to let them down. To make sure this is sustainable, we made a rule where we can only put 1 to 2 tasks per day because if it’s too time consuming no one would want to do it. Due to the limited the number of tasks, we often use it to put our daily highlights there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily highlight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this concept is super simple but I find it to be super effective. Each day I have a daily highlight which is basically the most important task I want to get done that day. Even if I get nothing else done it still allows me to be satisfied with my day. Additionally, once I complete my daily highlight, it usually gives me the momentum to help me complete everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Habit Tracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is definitely the best way to be help you manage any habits you want to be consistent with.  The reason why I love habit trackers is that they are extremely effective. If I don’t a complete a habit for awhile, I have to keep checking it off as red which bothers me a lot because it shows that I’ve been lazy on that particular habit which gives me motivation to resume my habit again. On the other hand, if I’ve been completing my habit everyday, it feels super satisfying and it creates a streak that I don’t want to break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self Reflection Study Sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pomodoro technique is basically where you study for 25 min and take a 5 min break or study for 50 min and take a 10 min break. To further improve my studying efficiency, after each session is over I reflect on how each session went. This allows to learn more what I need to do study better and create an environment that I need to thrive. There are 4 main factors that I look at to see how productive I actually was while studying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus level (1 to 10)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What went well?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What went wrong?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could I improve?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>